# Hyemi Song

HOME https://hvemisong.com/ PORTFOLIO https://bohvemian.com/ EMAIL hsong02@cs.umd.edu

# Summary

Hyemi Song is a researcher and designer interested in Information Visualization, HCI, and Immersive Analytics. Currently, she studies the complex interplay between Natural Language and Data Visualization in XR within generative Al-powered immersive analytics under the supervision of Dr. Amitabh Varshney. **Immigrant Status**: US Permanent Resident (EB-1A Extraordinary Ability, self-petitioned, 2021)

# **Educational Background**

**University of Maryland**, College Park, USA, 2022-Present Ph.D. Computer Science

**University of Maryland**, College Park, USA, 2022-2024 Master of Science, Computer Science

**Rhode Island School of Design**, Providence, USA Master of Fine Arts, Digital + Media

**University of the Arts London**, London, UK Foundation, Visual Communication Design

**The Catholic University of Korea**, Seoul, Korea Bachelor of Science, Molecular Biology

# Research Experience

**University of Maryland College Park**, USA, 2022 - Present **Position**: Research Assistant (Advisor: Dr. Amitabh Varshney)

Labs: UMD Graphics and Visual Informatics Laboratory, Human-Computer Interaction Lab Currently working on Natural Language and Data Visualization Interplay in XR within generative Al-powered

immersive analytics.

Massachusetts Institute of Technology, MIT Senseable City Lab, Cambridge, USA, 2016 - 2017

Position: Research Fellow, Data Visualization Specialist

Developed an award-winning project, Cityways, Driving DNA, Pisa Pool, Urban Exposure, and more.

NAVER Corporation, Seoul, Korea, 2011 - 2014

Position: UX Researcher

Designed mobile/web UX/UI for a Social Network Service, 'me2day' (Korea's equivalent of Twitter), and designed a search engine, 'NAVER' (the largest search engine in Korea).

### **Teaching Experience**

University of Maryland College Park, 2022 Spring/Summer, 2023 Spring/Summer/Fall

Position: Teaching Assistant

Class: Introduction to Data Science, Web Application Development with JavaScript

Rhode Island School of Design, 2016 Winter

Position: Instructor

Class: Measuring the Universe (2016 RISD Winter Session)

## **Industry Experience**

Microsoft, Redmond, USA, 2019 - 2022

Position: Senior Designer

Specialized in Data Visualization, Designed for Machine Learning and Al products. Designed Error Analysis Dashboard, Azure Machine Learning Studio, and more.

Datadog Inc, New York, USA, 2017 - 2019

Position: Product Designer

Specialized in Data Visualization. Designed/developed Service Map, Host, and Infra map.

VINYL Interactive, Seoul, Korea, 2010 - 2011

Position: UX/UI designer

Designed and developed the web/mobile Service Strategies & Proposals, interactive installations, and digital media promotions for 10+ clients; SAMSUNG, Korea

Telecommunication, and more. KT Olleh Square won a prize from the iF design awards.

2015 Brothers, Seoul, Korea, 2009 - 2010

Position: Art Director

Designed and directed advertising projects for 20+ clients, including SKTelecom,

SAMSUNG, and Korea Technology.

**PXD**, Seoul, Korea, 2008 - 2009 Position: Interaction Designer

Developed and designed mobile/web UI/UX services for clients including SKTelecom and SAMSUNG.

Kiz Entertainment, Seoul, Korea, 2004

Position: Clay Animator

Participated in Clay animations for an advertisement, and TV Series with 5+ Clients, including Korean

Broadcasting System and Dino land.

eyeballNYC, New York, USA, 2015, Samsung Electronics, Seoul, Korea, 2007, Cheil World Wide, Seoul, Korea, 2006

Position: Design Intern

#### **Research Projects**

- 1. Natural Language and Data Visualization Interplay in Immersive Environments
  - [1] NL-Driven Interactions in Generative Al-Infused Immersive Analytics, 2023 Present (W.I.P.)

Role: First Author

[2] Interaction Authoring for Data Visualization in Immersive Environments, 2022 - Present (W.I.P.)

Role: First Author

#### **Publications**

- [3] Hannah K. Bako, Xinyi Liu, Grace Ko, **Hyemi Song**, Leilani Battle & Zhicheng Liu, Unveiling How Examples Shape Data Visualization Design Outcomes, **IEEE VIS 2024**, <u>Link</u>
- [2] Zongxia Li, Paiheng Xu, Fuxiao Liu, **Hyemi Song**, Towards understanding in-context learning with contrastive demonstrations and saliency maps, **Preprint 2023**, <a href="arxiv.org/abs/2307.05052">arxiv.org/abs/2307.05052</a>
- [1] Hyemi Song, Walking in a Place, Walkestra, Rhode Island School of Design, MFA Thesis 2016

# **Books & Book Chapters**

- [2] Hyemi Song, Solar System, Annual Student Artists' Book Juried Contest, Rhode Island School of Design, 2015
- [1] Steven Heller, Rick Landers, Raw Data, (Published Works: The temperature of my mind, Visualizing works), 2014

## Grants, Fellowships & Scholarships

**ACM DIS**, USA - Awarded one-year ACM Professional Membership for paper review contribution, 2024

IEEEVIS, USA - Inclusive and Diversity Scholarship, 2023

University of Maryland College Park, USA - Dean's Fellowship/Assistantship, 2022-Present

Massachusetts Institute of Technology, USA - Fellowship, 2016 - 2017 Rhode Island School of Design, USA - Assistantship/Fellowship, 2014 - 2016 Samsung Art & Design Institute, Korea - Scholarship, 2007

## Jury, Peer Review, Advising service

ACM Designing Interactive Systems- Reviewer, 2024 - Present, (Full papers: 2024)

IEEEVIS - Reviewer, 2023 - Present, (Full papers: 2023, Short papers: 2024)

PacificVis - Juror, 2022 - 2023

IEEEVIS Arts Program - Program Committee, 2018 - Present

A' Design Award & Competition, Italy - Jury Member, 2018 - 2022

Brown University, Computer Science Department, USA - Portfolio Reviewer, 2019 - 2021

Apexart, USA - Jury Member, 2017

## Invited talks, Lectures, Workshop (Selected)

Ohio State University Ohio, USA, 2022

Lecture: Data and Human Communication

GyeongGi Cultural Foundation, Seoul, Korea, 2021

Lecture: Data as a communication medium: art, design, and human

San Jose State University San Jose, USA, 2021

Lecture: Data and Human Communication

Workshop: Measuring the temperature of my mind

#### **Awards**

ACM Designing Interactive Systems, USA - Awarded for Best Paper Review Contribution, 2024

IEEE Arts Program, Melbourne, Australia - Accepted for exhibition, 2023 (Project: Solar System)

A'Design Award and Competition, Italy - Winner (Gold), 2018-2019

Information is Beautiful Awards, USA - Long List, 2018

World Changing Ideas Awards (by Fast Company), USA - Finalist, 2018

IEEE Arts Program, Berlin, Germany - Accepted for exhibition

A'Design Award and Competition, Italy - Winner (Iron), 2016-2017

53rd American Graphic Design Awards, GDUSA, USA -Winner (Student), 2016

Spark International Design Awards, USA - Finalist, 2016

Annual Student Artists' Book Juried Contest, USA - Accepted for exhibition and publication at RISD Fleet Library, 2015

Adobe Design Achievement Awards, USA - Semifinalist, 2008, 2015, 2016

Adobe Design Achievement Awards, USA - Honorable Mention 2007

IF Design Award, USA - Winner, 2010

Good Design Award, Japan - Winner, 2010

Seoul Design Olympiad 2009, Korea - Winner (Honorable Mention), 2009

SADI Graduation Award, Korea - Experimental Portfolio Winner, 2008

11th Environmental Management Corporation Award, Korea - Winner, 2006

#### Media Appearance

Monthly Design (Oldest Korean Design Magazine), Seoul, Korea, 2018

Feature Interview, Title - Data Visualization Designer, Hyemi Song / Link

Data Vis Today, USA, 2018

Feature Interview, Podcast (Episode 13) / Link

IdN, Hong Kong, 2018

Featured article (Project: CityWays), IdN is an international Design Magazine / Link

The Guardian, USA, 2016

News Article (Project: Urban Exposure), Data Visualization at MIT Senseable City Lab / Link

Visual Loop, Brazil, 2012

Featured article, Title - Finding stories of data visualization from twitter / Link

Information Aesthetics, USA, 2011

Featured article, Title - Visualizing Works: Hyemi Song's Innovative Portfolio / Link

Visualising Data, USA, 2011

Featured article, Title - Visualizing Works: Hyemi Song's Innovative Portfolio

Sadi Vision, Korea, 2011

Featured article (Project: Visualizing Works)

IF Online Gallery, USA, 2010

IF Online Gallery (Project: KT Olleh Square) **2009 Seoul Design Olympiad**, Korea, 2009

Annual publication for winners

Adobe Design Achievement Award Online Gallery, USA, 2008

ADAA Online Gallery (Project: The temperature of my mind

#### **Exhibitions**

IEEE Arts Program, Melbourne, Australia, 2023 (Project: Solar System)

Design Korea Festival 2020, Design Beyond Data, @Coex, Seoul, Korea, (Declined) 2020

IEEE Arts Program, Berlin, Germany, 2018

A'design Award Winner exhibition, @Mood, Italy, 2017

Shenzhen Design Week, @Shenzhen Convention Center, China, 2017

RISD Nature Lab anniversary exhibition, @Waterman Gallery, USA, 2017

Internet Festival, @Waterman Gallery, Pisa, Italy, 2016

RISD Graduate Exhibition, @Providence Convention Center, USA

Dark Matter, @RISD Sol Koffler Gallery, USA

Image Landscapes, @RISD Gelman Gallery, USA

Annual Student Artists' Book Exhibition, @RISD Fleet Library, USA

2009 Seoul Design Olympiad, @Jamsil Main Stadium, Korea

Sharing Experience 2009, @Zero one center Gallery, Korea

Onepiece Magazine Ceremony Party 500, Korea

Reviewing Hanul Exhibition, @Space Hiut, Korea

GUANGZHOU Design Korea Exhibition, Guangzhou, China

2nd D.I.P. Exhibition, @SADI Space Gallery, Korea

21st D.I.P. Exhibition, @SADI Space Gallery, Korea

SADI Graduation Exhibition, @SADI Space Gallery, Korea

Hanul Exhibition, @Shinhan Gallery, Korea

Chelsea College of Arts Graduation Exhibition, @Hugon Road Gallery, UK

#### **Permanent Collections**

Solar System (Artbook), RISD Fleet Library, Rhode Island School of Design, 2015

### Coursework (UMD)

Explainable Natural Language Processing Link

Natural Language Processing Link

User Experience Research Methods Link

Information Visualization Link

Advances in XR Link

Info-Centric Design System Link
Interactive Technologies in Human-Computer Interaction
Visual Analytics
Bioinformatics (AU)
Embodied Media Design (AU)

# **Skillsets**

Front, Backend, Data Visualization, Data Science, AR/VR Javascript, React, Redux, Express.js, MongoDB, Python, HTML, CSS, C# D3js, Vegalit, Matplotlib, Three.js, PyTorch, Unity

#### Design & Research

Graphic Design, UX/UI design, Interaction Design, UX Research, Academic Research